So where might you want to take a
function as an input? Well, what it lets
you do is it lets you write a function
that takes a function and calls it. So
I'm going to demonstrate this by
commenting out we don't need that last
function. So I'm going to comment that
out for now. But we do need our cleanup
string function. So what I'm going to do
is I'm going to create a string array.
And I'm just going to Whoa.
I'm going to create a string array. And
I'm just going to pass in
um random things. So we'll say hello.
And that one has a lot of spaces at the
front. We're going to put spaces and
then type we're going to actually type
world and put a lot of spaces at the
end. And then we're going to put spaces
and then hi and then spaces. So as you
can see, we have a string array. Well,
let's write a function. We're going to
call this function pro apply to array.
What it's going to do is it's going to
take an input array and it's going to
take an input function.
Then what we're going to do is we're
going to loop over that array. So we'll
say for let I or sorry counter equal
zero counter is less than input
array.length
Because if we get an array here, then it
should have a property called length,
which means we can loop over this array.
Then I'll put a semicolon, and then
we'll say counter plus+. So thus far,
all this function does is it takes in an
input array, and it takes in an input
function. It starts a counter at zero,
loops for the length of the array. So in
this case, this array has 0 1 2 items.
So, we're going to start at zero and
we're going to go almost up to three,
but not quite including three, which
means we're going to go 0, one, two, and
we're going to increment by one each
time. So, hopefully you've watched the
array videos and you understand how to
loop through an array. Okay, what I want
to do is I want to go to the string
array at the counter position. So,
meaning the first time this loop goes
through, I want to go to this very first
position. And what I want to do is I
want to set it equal to um the result of
calling input function and passing in as
an input.
Oh, and I'm sorry. This isn't supposed
to be string array. This is supposed to
be input array. So I'm going to take
whichever array I receive. I'm going to
go to the zero position. If we pass in
string array, the zero position is going
to be this hello. And I want to set it
equal to calling whichever function we
pass in. And um as an input to that
function, I'm going to take in this
exact same thing. So
what I'm saying is take this string with
a lot of spaces that says hello,
pass it in to whatever function I happen
to be calling. Take the result and store
it back where this hello was.
And then I put a semicolon. And then I'm
going to return
the input array.
And so I'm going to call this I'm going
to say let results equal
apply to array. What am I going to take?
What is the input array I want to give
it? Well, I want to give it string
array. What is the input function I want
to give it? Well, I want to give it
cleanup string. And then um I'm going to
console
log the result. Okay, so let's save this
and come over to our running code and
stop it and reload the page. Okay, if we
look at our console, we can see that it
says hello world and hi. But let's just
go over to sources and run our debugger.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to
put a break point on line 33 and I'm
going to reload the page. Okay, it says
result is going to be equal to whatever
the result of calling apply to array is.
Apply to array is give receiving an
input of an array which has strings with
different casing and spaces in random
places. And then it's also going to
receive an input of cleanup function.
When we hit next, input array is storing
that string array we just passed in.
input function is storing the cleanup
function we just passed in. Which means
if we hit next and we start our counter,
our counter is at zero. If we go to
input array at the zero position, that's
going to be the text with a lot of
spaces that says hello and a closing
space. And we're going to call input
function. What is input function? It's
the cleanup string function we wrote
earlier. So we'll hit next.
And it comes here. What is messy string?
Well, it's that spaces with hello inside
of it. So, we're going to trim it and
turn it all to uppercase and return it.
And now, if we look at our input array,
we can see that hello is in all
uppercases and all the spaces have been
removed. We're going to increment our
counter. Um, now we're going to input
array at the one position, which means
we're taking world with spaces on the
end, and we're going to pass it into
input function. What is input function?
Well, it's still the cleanup string
function that we used earlier. So, we'll
hit next. We'll trim it, convert it to
uppercase. And now if we look at our
input array, we've seen we've cleaned up
the first two strings. And we run it and
clean up the next string. Return our
array. And it returns to result. And now
result is storing hello, world, and hi.
All in uppercase with no spaces. So
that's cool and all. We probably didn't
need to write a function passed into a
function for that. But why did we do
that? Well, let's say I write another
function and I call this function
um
round
and we take in a number
and we return math
round
um and it says what value do you want to
round the number and it rounds it to the
nearest integer. So, what this does is
it takes in a number and rounds it to
the nearest integer.
Well, now if we have another array,
we'll call it numbum array and we'll set
it equal to a bunch of numbers. So, 3.5,
2.3,
5.5.
The great thing about our apply to array
function is it doesn't care what array
we give it or what function we give it.
So that means we can reuse our apply to
array function and we can say let result
2 equal apply to array. We can take in
the number array. We can take in the
round function. And now if we save it,
we can come over here and if we come to
our console. Oh, I forgot to log the
results. console.log
log result two
and we reload the page. We come to the
console. We get hello world and hi. That
string was clean. All those strings were
cleaned up. Then we get four 2 five and
five.
Well, how did that happen? Well, we
already wrote an apply to array function
and it can take in an array. So the
first time it took in this string array
and what function did it apply to every
item in the array? It applied cleanup
string. Well, the next time we called
it, we called it and we passed in this
number array. And what function did we
apply to it? The round function. So why
is this nice? Well, it allows us to
write a function that takes other
functions and applies it to an array.
There wasn't a function previously
called apply to array, but we were able
to create one and we made it flexible
enough that it can take in any function
that you want and it can apply it to an
array. And the nice thing about this is
it can take in built-in functions. So we
could say let result three equal apply
to array and we could take the number
array as an input and we could apply
math.round.
And instead of calling this round
function, we could just directly pass in
the math.round function and it will
apply it to our array.
So, um, the nice thing about being able
to take a function as an input is that
you can call it and you don't need to
care which function it is. We didn't
care which function they passed us. We
just called it on the array and applied
the result to the array.